Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Collection on Individuals WEB.ARC.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
- Rogovin, Milton Archived Website, Sep 9, 2010; Rogovin, Milton, 1909-2011.
  Milton Rogovin (1909-2011) was a social documentary photographer in New York City. Rogovin was called before the House Un-American Activities Committee in 1957, which inspired him to use his camera and began making images that communicated his desire for a just and equal society. Rogovin’s first book, The Forgotten Ones, is made up of photographs of coal miners from all over the world. One of his other projects "The Forgotten Ones," are sequential portraits taken over three decades of over a hundred families who resided on Buffalo’s impoverished Lower West Side. Rogovin’s photographs are being preserved at the Library of Congress. This website is his official webpage.
  Communists |z United States.; Documentary photography |z United States.
- Ruppert, Michael C. (From the Wilderness' Peak Oil Blog) Archived Website, Jul 27, 2009 - Oct 12, 2013; Ruppert, Michael C.
  From the Wilderness' Peak Oil Blog is a blog created by Michael C. Ruppert as the successor website to FromTheWilderness.com. The blog covers topics regarding peak oil, which is the point in time when the maximum rate of global petroleum extraction is reached, after which the rate of production enters terminal decline. The blog is maintained by Jenna Orkin. This blog is also published on http://www.collapsenet.com.
  Economics.; Hubbert peak theory.; News web sites |z United States.; Oil industries.
- Sanders, Bernie Archived Website, Aug 21, 2010 - ongoing; Sanders, Bernie
  Bernie Sanders (born September 8, 1941 in Brooklyn) is the junior United States Senator from Vermont. Previously, Sanders represented Vermont's at-large district in the United States House of Representatives. Sanders also served as mayor of Burlington, Vermont. He is the longest serving independent member of Congress in American history, and a self-identified democratic socialist. He is the first person elected to the U.S. Senate to identify as a socialist. Sanders caucuses with the Democratic Party and is counted as a Democrat for the purposes of committee assignments, but because he does not belong to a formal political party, he appears as an independent on the ballot. This website is his official webpage.
  Legislators |z United States.; Socialists |z United States.
- Seeger, Peter Archived Website, Jun 21, 2012 - ongoing; Seeger, Pete, 1919-
  This is the official website of Pete Seeger (born May 3, 1919), an American folk singer and activist. The website contains information on his music, recent collaboration projects, and his label, Appleseed.
  Folk singers |z United States.; Political ballads and songs |z United States.
- Shakur, Assata Archived Website, Jul 30, 2009-Jun 24, 2014; Shakur, Assata.
  Assata Olugbala Shakur (born July 16, 1947, as JoAnne Chesimard) is an African-American activist and escaped convict who was a member of the Black Panther Party (BPP) and Black Liberation Army (BLA). On May 2, 1973, she was involved in a shootout on the New Jersey turnpike, resulting in the death of a state trooper and BLA member Zayd Malik Shakur. Shakur spent six and a half years in prison before escaping in 1979 to New Jersey. She has been living in Cuba since 1984. This is her official support website.
- Singer, Peter Archived Website, Aug 12, 2010 - ongoing; Singer, Peter
  Peter Singer (1946-) is a philosopher specializing in ethics, and since 1999 has been Professor of Bioethics at the University Centre for Human Values, Princeton University. Singer's philosophical interests are largely in the fields of ethics and politics, particularly practical problems such as abortion, euthanasia, and our treatment of animals. His greatest influence has been in the field of animal ethics. In his 1975 book Animal Liberation he argues that although human beings have a long history of mistreating animals, there is no moral justification for such behaviour, [due to] the wrongness of causing unnecessary suffering. His is also president of Animal Rights International. Singer's book had a tremendous effect — not only on individuals, bringing many people, philosophers and non- philosophers alike, to vegetarianism, but also on society. We now take the notion of animal liberation for granted as a respectable moral cause; when Singer was writing, it was widely seen as the concern of eccentrics and little old ladies with too many cats. He has also argued that individuals in affluent societies are morally obligated to contribute a substantial portion of their income to people in poor countries, and to not to do so is an action causing needless suffering and death. Singer's conclusions concerning abortion, euthanasia and infanticide are controversial. He argues that, although they can suffer, the unborn, infants and severely disabled people lack the ability to plan and anticipate their future; it's therefore morally permissible under certain circumstances, to end their lives.
  Animal rights activists.; Animal rights.; Ethicists |z United States.; Ethics and public life; Philosophers.
- Stewart, Lynne Archived Website, Jul 7, 2009 - ongoing; Stewart, Lynne.
  Lynne Irene Stewart (born October 8, 1939) is a former attorney who represented controversial, poor, and often unpopular defendants. She was convicted on charges of conspiracy and providing material support to terrorists in 2005, and sentenced to 28 months in prison. Her felony conviction led to her being automatically disbarred. She was convicted of helping pass messages from her client, Sheikh Omar Abdel-Rahman, an Egyptian cleric convicted of planning terror attacks, to his followers in al-Gama'a al- Islamiyya, an organization designated as a Foreign Terrorist Organization by the United States Secretary of State. She was re-sentenced on July 15, 2010, to 10 years in prison in light of her alleged perjury at her trial, and her lack of remorse after her initial sentencing. This website works to raise funds for Stewart’s legal defense and work to release Stewart.
  Terrorism--United States.
- Support Marie Mason Archived Website, May 2, 2011 - Aug 1, 2014; Mason, Marie
  This website is a support website for Marie Mason. She is an environmental activist from Cincinnati, Ohio, who in 2009 was sentenced to 22 years after admitting 13 counts of arson and property damage amounting to 4 million dollars to an office connected to GMO (Genetically Modified Organism) research. Mason, a member of the Earth Liberation Front, was prosecuted for a 1999 attack on a building at Michigan State University, East Lansing, Michigan, that caused more than 1 million dollars in damages, undertaken as a protest against research into genetically modified crops. The website works to raise awareness and funds for Mason and work for her freedom.
  Ecoterrorism |x United States.
- Support Marius Mason Archived Website, Nov 5, 2014-ongoing
  This website is a support website for Marius Mason. He is an environmental activist from Cincinnati, Ohio, who in 2009 was sentenced to 22 years after admitting 13 counts of arson and property damage amounting to 4 million dollars to an office connected to GMO (Genetically Modified Organism) research. Mason, a member of the Earth Liberation Front, was prosecuted for a 1999 attack on a building at Michigan State University, East Lansing, Michigan, that caused more than 1 million dollars in damages, undertaken as a protest against research into genetically modified crops. In 2014, Marius changed his name from Marie to reflect his masculine gender identity. The website works to raise awareness and funds for Mason and work for her freedom.
  Mason, Marie; Ecoterrorism |x United States.
- Swartz, Aaron Archived Website, Feb 13, 2013; Swartz, Aaron, 1986-2013
  Aaron Swartz (1986-2013) was an internet activist, computer programmer, and writer. Swartz was involved in the development of the web feed format RSS, the organization Creative Commons, the website framework web.py, and the user generated content website, Reddit. Swartz also founded Demand Progress, an online progressive policy organization, best known for its campaigns against Stop Online Piracy Act (SOPA) and the PROTECT IP Act (PIPA). His website contains a bio and his blog.
  Internet |x Law and legislation |z United States.
- Tambellini, Aldo Archived Website, Dec 7, 2012 - ongoing; Tambellini, Aldo
  Aldo Tambellini was born in Syracuse, New York in 1930 but grew up in Italy. In 1946, Aldo returned to the United States. With a full scholarship at Syracuse University he received a BFA in Painting, ‘54 and a Teaching Fellowship at the University of Notre Dame, MFA ’59. In 1959, Aldo moved to New York City’s Lower East Side. He founded the underground, "counter-culture" group, "Group Center," which organized alternative ways and non- traditional presentation of the artists’ work to the public. He pioneered in the video art movement in the late 60’s. In 1965, he began painting directly on film beginning his "Black Film Series" of which, "Black TV," (made using both film and video) was the winner of the International Grand Prix, Oberhausen Film Festival, 1969. Simultaneously, Aldo began a series of "Electromedia Performances" which organically brought together, projected paintings, film, video, poetry, light, dance, sound and live musicians. He founded the Gate Theatre, the only daily public theatre showing avant- garde independent filmmakers and in 1967, he co-founded with Otto Piene, the Black Gate, a second theatre which presented live multi-media (Electromedia) performances and installations. From 1976 to 1984, Aldo was a Fellow at the Center for Advanced Visual Studies at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. There he conducted workshops and organized with "communicationsphere" a series of international interactive Media Communication Projects. Since ’84, he has concentrated on poetry and performing his poetry with music and video projection. In 2005 Aldo produced a digital film, "Listen" which incorporates his anti-war and political poetry, animation/video and film clips. This film won First Place in the "Short Experimental Film by an Independent Filmmaker" category at the New England Film Festival in October 2005 and at the Syracuse International Film Festival in 2006. In 2007 Aldo was awarded the "Lifetime Achievement Award" from Syracuse University at the 2007 Syracuse International Film Festival. The same year he received the Keys to the City of Cambridge from Mayor Ken Reeves in recognition of his contribution to the cultural environment of Cambridge. In 2010 Aldo was awarded a Gold medal from the Italian Government, Lucchesi Nel Mondo Organization, in recognition of his lifetime achievement in the Arts. The website contains examples of his art.
  Anarchists |z New York (State) |z New York.; Art |x Political aspects |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Vote Reverend Billy For Mayor Of NYC Archived Website, Dec 15, 2009 - ongoing; Talen, Bill.
  Vote Reverend Billy was the campaign website of Bill Talen’s campaign for mayor in 2009. Talen ran under the Green Party platform. Talen leads the Church of Life After Shopping, which is an activist performance group.
  Community organization |z New York (State) |z New York.; Performance artists--New York (State)--New York.; Radicals |z New York (State) |z New York.
- West, Cornel Archived Website, Aug 7, 2010 - ongoing; West, Cornel
  Cornel Ronald West (born June 2, 1953) is an African American philosopher, author, critic, actor, and civil rights activist, as well as a prominent member of the Democratic Socialists of America. West currently serves as the Class of 1943 University Professor at Princeton University, where he teaches in the Center for African American Studies and in the department of Religion. West is known for his combination of political and moral insight and criticism, and his contribution to the post-1960s civil rights movement. The bulk of his work focuses upon the role of race, gender, and class in American society and the means by which people act and react to their "radical conditionedness." West draws intellectual contributions from such diverse traditions as the African American Baptist Church, pragmatism and transcendentalism. Dr. West is the author or Race Matters, 19l other books, including an autobiography, Brother West: Living and Loving Out Loud, numerous articles, and a rap record. West also offers commentary weekly on The Tavis Smiley Show from PRI (Public Radio International).
  African American philosophy; Philosophers.; Socialists |z United States.
- Zinn, Howard Archived Website, Jul 1, 2010 - ongoing; Zinn, Howard, 1922-2010
  This is the website of Howard Zinn (1922-2010), the noted radical U.S. historian and author of "A People's History of the United States." In addition to a biography and bibliography, the site contains print interviews, essays and commentary, audio and video, and information about The People Speak, the documentary based on the live performances of Howard Zinn and Anthony Arnove's Voices of a People's History of the United States.
  Historians |z United States.